What we're going to do in this video and a few other videos is we are going
在本视频及后续几个视频中
to look at an introduction to react-navigation,
我们将介绍 react-navigation
which is a routing library for react-native.
它是一个 react-native 导航库
Now, react-navigation is all about navigators.
react-navigation 的主要功能是提供导航器
You'll notice here that by default,
默认情况下
they give us three navigators: TabNavigator, StackNavigator, and DrawerNavigator.
它们提供了三个导航器：TabNavigator、StackNavigator 和 DrawerNavigator
Navigators allow you to define your application's navigation structure.
借助导航器 你能够定义应用的导航结构
So what we're going to look at in this video is TabNavigator, and basically,
在本视频中 我们将了解 TabNavigator
what it's going to allow us to do is it's going to allow us to have
它使我们能够在应用中添加标签页
tabs on our app that we can switch back and forth from,
并在标签页之间来回切换
and then render different components,
然后渲染不同的组件
whether it's either the Home component or the Dashboard component.
无论是 Home 组件还是 Dashboard 组件
So what we're going to do is,
转到这里
say right here, let's create a new variable.
新建一个变量
We will just call it TabNavigator,
称之为 Tabs
and if you haven't already and you want to play around with this as well,
如果你想了解下该组件 但是尚未安装
go ahead and yarn add react-navigation.
请运行 yarn add react-navigation
So inside of TabNavigator,
我们在 TabNavigator 中
we pass an object,
传入一个对象
and the properties on this object are going to
该对象上的属性将为
be the specific routes or the specific tabs.
具体的路径或标签页
So what we're going to do is we can come in here and say, Home,
我们在这里输入 Home
which is going to be the first tab,
它将是第一个标签页
and we can come in here and say,
然后在这里
we want the screen to be Home.
将 screen 设为 Home
And the second tab is going to be Dashboard,
第二个标签页将是 Dashboard
and we want the screen that is going to show to be this Dashboard component right here.
我们希望屏幕显示这个 Dashboard 组件
So now, what TabNavigator returns is that actual component.
TabNavigator 返回的是实际组件
So what we can do is, down here,
我们可以转到这里
we can actually just render the component as we're used to.
像之前一样渲染该组件
So now, if we look at our app,
看看应用效果
you'll notice that this is iOS on the left and this is Android on the right.
左边的是 iOS 右边的是 Android
You'll notice that the layout and the styles,
你会发现二者之间的布局和样式
it's a little bit different because what's going on
不太一样
here is iOS has its own look and feel,
因为 iOS 具有自己的外观和行为
Android has its own look and feel.
Android 也具有自己的外观和行为
When you use TabNavigator on iOS,
当你在 iOS 上使用 TabNavigator 时
you get tabs that look like this.
标签页是这样的
Notice you can't really see it too well,
看得不太清楚
but this text up here is changing.
但是这里的文本的确在变化
And then also on Android,
此外 在 Android 上
we can go ahead and switch back and forth between these two tabs as well.
我们也可以在这两个标签页之间切换
Now, if you want to add an icon
如果你想向此 iOS 应用添加图标
to this iOS app because it looks a little better without it,
因为没有图标的话 看起来太平淡
what we can do is,
我们可以...
notice that we have already imported our icons from vector-icons.
我们已经从 vector-icons 中导入 Ionicons
So inside of TabNavigator,
在 TabNavigator 中
what we can do is we can come in here and we can add some navigationOptions.
我们可以在这里添加一些 navigationOptions
We're going to give it a tabBarIcon,
添加 tabBarIcon
and then what we will do is we want to render FontAwesome.
我们想要渲染 FontAwesome
The name of this is going to be home.
名称将为 home
We'll give it a size of 30.
size 设为 30
Color, we'll just say, black for now.
color 暂时设为 black
And we're going to do something really similar for the Dashboard screen,
Dashboard 屏幕的设置非常相似,
but instead of home, this is going to be dashboard.
但是将这个 home 改为 dashboard
And so now, notice that we have these tabs down here that we're switching between,
现在 下面出现了这两个可以相互切换的标签页
and what's nice about React Navigation is it's really customizable.
React Navigation 的强大之处是可以轻松地自定义
If we look at the documentation just for TabNavigator itself,
我们看看 TabNavigator 的官方文档
notice here are some examples.
这里有一些示例
But down here, there is all these things we can configure.
下面是所有这些我们可以配置的设置
We can configure the tabBarPosition,
我们可以配置 tabBarPosition
initialRouteNames, paths and then,
initialRouteName、path
we can start configuring some of the styles whether it's the activeTintColor,
我们还可以配置一些样式 无论是 activeTintColor
how to showLabel, the inactiveTintColor,
还是如何显示标签、inactiveTintColor
all of these different examples.
等等
So again, if you need to do something with React Navigation,
如果你需要用 React Navigation 实现某个效果
odds are you can do it because there are a ton of options here.
一般都能实现 因为这里有无数的选项
Now, it may get a little bit overwhelming because what you end up doing is passing in
可能会有点繁杂 因为你会传入大量的对象
huge objects like this to configure your routes.
就像这里一样 从而配置路由
But again, it's nice because basically,
但是很强大
anything you want to do, you can do it.
因为你可以实现任何效果